

Siddharth Patel

919-888-3535| 305 Legault Drive, Cary, NC, 27513 | s.siddharthpatel@gmail.com | github.com/SIddharth3791

Professional Summary

Result- oriented Software Engineer with relevant experience in design and development. Proficient in different platforms and languages. Strong Background of software architecture, class design and program documentation

Technical Skills

Software: Java, Swift, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JUnit Testing, MySQL, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, BASCOM

Platforms: Amazon Web Services, MongoDB, Windows, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, iOS, Android Source Control tools: GitHub, Rally, Artifactory, Jenkins Build, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, Share Point

Application: Spring Tool Suit, Eclipse, NetBeans, Xcode, Android Studio, Rally, LucidChart, PostMan Rest Client, MS-Access

Technical Interest: - Cloud Computing with AWS, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, MongoDB Agile SDLC, Team Software Process, Test Automation

Languages: English, Gujarati, Hindi (Native language)

Education

East Carolina University, Greenville, NC Greenville, NC Master of Computer Software Engineering, GPA 3.5/4/0 December 2016 Gujarat Technology University, Gujarat, India Gujarat, India Bachelors of Electronics and Communication Engineering, GPA 3.5/4.0 June 2013

Relevant Projects and Experience

SanityTest Microservice using Spring Framework:

Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, STS, PCF(PaaS), RabbitMO, Artifactory and GitHub

EMC Corporation

- Worked with Unity Cloud Team at EMC, developed Microservice name 'SanityTest' and deployed on Cloud Foundry
- Feature of that Microservice was to test the whole environment on Cloud Foundry before production stage
- Got on hand experience with Agile Methodology, Scrum and tools like Rally

Fit Geek iPhone Application:

Technologies: Xcode, Swift, Amazon Web Service, MongoDB and GitHub

East Carolina University

- Design and Developed iOS application to cover all aspect of fitness, from Diet to workouts
- Used different frameworks like UIKits, MapKit, Parse and Bolts.
- All Data is stored on MongoDB cluster that runs on AWS Elastic Cloud Computing (EC2)

Instant messaging chat Application:

Technologies: like java, NeatBeans and GitHub

Third Semester **East Carolina University**

- Several Java technologies, like networking sockets and I/O, and Multithreading were used to develop.
- GUI for client and server was developed using Swing package
- Instant Messaging happens in real time, Application can support two or more user at same time.

4. **Restaurant management System:**

Technologies:- Java, MySQL, Java Server Page, HTML5, CSS3 and GitHub

Second Semester East Carolina University

Final Year Project

- Project was developed in Team, which helped me to gain leadership and communication skills to express ideas more efficiently.
- Developed Front-end via Java Server PageHTML5/CSS/JavaScript
- MySQL was used to developed application backend and storage.

5. Gym workout Planner:

Technologies: Java, PostgreSQl and GitHub

Third Semester

Internship

East Carolina University

May 2016 – August 2016

Developed a windows based application, Swing Java Package was used to develop GUI

PostgreSQL was used as backend and storage for user entered data

Employment History

EMC Corporation - Software Engineer Intern

EMC Corporation is worlds largest provider data storage systems

- Worked closely with a Unity Cloud Team.
- Implemented Microservices, used Spring Framework and Java Programming language
- Worked Effectively in a Agile SDLC model and team environment
- Developed test automation packages for testing whole environment on Pivotal Cloud Foundry.
- Wrote technical design document for new Microservice. Included UML diagrams

East Carolina University, Department of construction management - Graduate Assistantship

August 2016 – Present

Assisted professor with design and documentation related to Recycle Concrete Aggregate.

East Carolina University, Global understanding department - Graduate Assistantship

August 2014 - May 2016

Assisted students with videoconference tool like Saba-meeting and mIRC. Design modules to guide students.

East Carolina University, Global Understanding department - Website developing Assistant

June 2015 - August 2015

Implemented full stack for the Global Understanding website. Used PHP and MySQL.

Embelink Electronics LTD - *Electronic Engineer*

August 2012 - May 2013

- Dealt with various electronic components like Micro-Controller, Heart Rate Sensor and GSM SIM 300
- Used BASCOM to Configure electronic component

Volunteer Experience

- Core Committee member for university level Technical event in an international fiesta of BITS "Aahvan 2012 "
- Actively involved with sports and physical events
- Member of charitable group name "AIESEC"